applydirect.com.au 2019-08-07

# ApplyDirect Privacy Policy

#### **Application of this policy**

We value the privacy of every person who visits our websites and we comply with applicable privacy laws in relation to the personal information we collect and hold. This Privacy Policy applies to personal information ApplyDirect collects from individuals we deal with (you, your), in particular our website visitors such as candidates and registered users. It explains what personal information we collect, how we use it to deliver a better candidate experience, how to request access and correction of personal information we hold about you, and how to opt out of direct marketing and complaint handling.

We also collect information about website visitors using cookies and other technologies. This information is anonymous, and we do not use cookies to collect personal information about you. For more information about our use of cookies and related technologies, please see our Cookies policy.

#### **Updates to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this policy from time to time to reflect our current practices and legal obligations. The updated policy will be published on the websites and will apply to your continued use of the websites

#### **What personal information do we collect and how?**

**_Account Registration:_** When you register as a candidate on ApplyDirect websites, or for Job Alerts, we may ask for personal information and information regarding your preferences as a jobseeker including:

  * Your first and last name;
  * Your preferred job types and job sub-types;
  * Your location, including your state and city;
  * Your email address;
  * A secure password
  * A personal photograph;
  * Your fit2work check status;
  * Where you heard about ApplyDirect.

When you contact us or make a request or complaint via our websites or by phone we collect your contact details and the information you submit.

When you apply for a job with us or submit your resume we collect details about your skills, qualifications, professional memberships or accreditations, interests, employment history, personal references and past responsibilities.

We also collect information about your consent to receive direct marketing and your preferences.

**_Use of Resume Review Tool_**

ApplyDirect has a partnership with a third party, _TopResume_ , who provide a tool through which users can submit a resume to be stored and reviewed by _TopResume_. When you submit your resume, your personal information will be collected by _TopResume_ and its Privacy Policy will apply. ApplyDirect does not collect or store resumes submitted via the Resume Review tool. To view _TopResume_ Privacy Policy follow [this link](https://www.topresume.com/privacy).

#### **Why do we collect and use your personal information?**

**Candidate Registration** \- we collect personal information about you as a jobseeker when you register as a candidate, in order to provide information about applicants to our clients who are advertising on the website.

**Job Alerts** \- to make it as easy as possible for jobseekers to find the job that they want, we send daily emails to Job Alert subscribers. In order to send you relevant jobs, we use the information you submit when you register for Job Alerts about the types of roles you’re looking for.

**Direct Marketing** \- we may also make registered job seekers aware of additional products and services with their consent where required by applicable laws. You may opt-out of receiving these materials by clicking "Unsubscribe" at the bottom of emails or by contacting [support@applydirect.com.au](mailto:support@applydirect.com.au).

#### **Who do we share your personal information with (including overseas)?**

Information submitted by registered users may be shared with job listing advertisers when a user submits an application through ApplyDirect. Resumes submitted through the Resume Review tool are shared with _TopResume_.

Where ApplyDirect discloses your personal information to its agents or sub-contractors for these purposes, the agent or sub-contractor in question will be obliged to use that personal information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. ApplyDirect may also disclose your personal information to the extent that it is required or authorized to do so by law, in connection with legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, and in order to establish, exercise or defend its legal rights.

#### **Your Rights and Complaints**

You have the right to access and request correction of any personal information we collect and hold about you. Registered candidates can access and update their details by logging in to their accounts and can permanently delete their registered profiles any time they wish. To request access to or correction of your personal information, contact [support@applydirect.com.au](mailto:support@applydirect.com.au).

Should you wish to submit a complaint regarding the processing of your personal data, you may do so by contacting [support@applydirect.com.au](mailto:support@applydirect.com.au). We may need to verify you and ask for further information so we can consider your complaint. We will provide you with our response and any resolution we propose within a reasonable time. If you are not satisfied with the resolution of your complaint, you are able to make a complaint to the Office of Australian Information Commission ([http://www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/)).

#### **Storing and securing Your personal information**

Candidate registration is collected and stored on an internal ApplyDirect database. Our servers are hosted by Amazon Web Services in Australia. Candidate profiles are deleted after three years of inactivity.

ApplyDirect will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse, access, disclosure or alteration of your personal information we hold. If you are concerned that any of the personal information we hold about you has been compromised you should contact us immediately so we can investigate the matter.

#### **Application of this policy**

We value the privacy of every person who visits our websites and we comply with applicable privacy laws in relation to the use of cookies. This Cookies Policy applies to the use of cookies to collect data on our website visitors (you, your), and explains how we use cookies, why we collect data using cookies and how you can opt out of a number of different services.

By using our websites, you consent to the collection and use of your user data by ApplyDirect as set out in this cookie policy. If we change our cookie policy in any way, these changes will be posted on this page.

Please email any questions, concerns or comments that you have about this policy to [support@applydirect.com.au](mailto:support@applydirect.com.au).

#### **What are cookies?**

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently to improve the user experience, as well as to provide certain information to the owners of the site including in relation to what ads to show you.

Our websites set cookies that remain on your computer for differing periods of time. Some expire at the end of each session and some remain for longer so that when you return to our website, you will have a better user experience.

#### **AdServing Cookies and Technology**

ApplyDirect serves display advertising on its websites on behalf of its advertising clients via the [DoubleClick AdExchange](https://www.doubleclickbygoogle.com/solutions/digital-marketing/ad-exchange/).

ApplyDirect uses a frequency cap when serving display advertisements, to ensure that we are limiting the number of times you see a specific advertisement each day. This is a protection afforded to the advertiser, to ensure they are not reaching you with the same message repeatedly over a short time period. To apply this frequency cap, ApplyDirect uses cookies to track the number of times you view or click on a display advertisement.

#### **Third-Party Measurement**

To better understand how users interact with our websites, we use a tracking code to collect aggregated information on website visitors’ behavior on the websites including:

  * What pages were visited, how many pages were visited during each visit, and the duration of users’ visits to the websites;
  * The devices used by website visitors.

This information allows us to make changes to the websites to improve your experience as a jobseeker.

Aggregated, non-personal data on impressions, clicks and applies for job listings on ApplyDirect websites are captured in order to provide reporting to our clients.

#### **Third-Party Advertising Data**

ApplyDirect may provide user behaviour data to third party data management platforms such as [Eyeota](https://www.eyeota.com/) to provide personalised advertising services.

AdServing data is collected using cookies, and ads are served accordingly through a third party AdServing product. Website data is collected and stored using a third-party tracking code.

#### **Managing Your Cookies Preferences**

Web browsers allow you to exercise some control of cookies through the browser settings. Most browsers enable you to block cookies or to block cookies from particular websites. Browsers can also help you to delete cookies when you close your browser. You should note however, that this may mean that any opt-outs or preferences you set on the site will be lost.

To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). You can opt out of a number of different third-party services via this [link](http://www.youronlinechoices.com.au/).

##### **Last updated: June 2018**
